All for fun and fun for all
Mickey, Donald, Goofy: The Three Musketeers is a adventure,
animation, comedy film directed by Donovan Cook.
In Disney's take on the Alexander Dumas tale, Mickey Mouse, Donald Duck and Goofy want nothing more than to perform
brave deeds on behalf of their queen (Minnie Mouse), but they're stymied by the head Musketeer, Pete.
Pete secretly wants to get rid of the queen, so he appoints Mickey and his bumbling friends as
guardians to Minnie, thinking such a maneuver will ensure his scheme's success.
The score features songs based on familiar classical melodies.
Mickey Mouse (voice), played by Wayne Allwine.
Donald Duck (voice), played by Tony Anselmo.
Goofy / Pluto / Additional Voices (voice), played by Bill Farmer.
Minnie (voice), played by Russi Taylor.
Daisy (voice), played by Tress MacNeille.
Pete (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Mickey, Donald, Goofy: The Three Musketeers, or simply The Three Musketeers, is a 2004 American animated direct-to-video musical adventure film based on the film adaptations
of the 1844 novel The Three Musketeers by Alexandre Dumas and the Mickey Mouse film series by Walt Disney and Ub Iwerks, as well as its expanded universe.
As the title suggests, it features Mickey Mouse, Donald Duck, and Goofy as the
three musketeers in their first full-length feature film together.
This film was directed by Donovan Cook, produced by Walt Disney
Pictures and the Australian office of Disneytoon Studios.
It was released directly to DVD and VHS on August 17, 2004, by Walt Disney Home Entertainment, and was later
re-released on Blu-ray Disc on August 12, 2014, coinciding with the film's 10th anniversary.
The film received generally mixed reviews from critics, who praised its musical numbers, action
sequences, and faithfulness to the original material, but was critical on other aspects.
The film explores themes of villain, anthropomorphism,
musketeer, cartoon mouse, cartoon dog.
The tone is lighthearted.